Guide to the John Gunther Papers 1935-1967
University of Chicago Library
- Series V: Inside U.S.A.
  - Subseries 53: Research Notes-Tennessee
    - Interview notes, David Lilienthal (Director, TVA) Kenneth McKellar (U.S. Senator) Edward Meeman (Editor, Memphis Press-Scimitar) Miscellaneous (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous notes Names, outline (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 54: Research Notes-Texas
    - Interview notes, Nathan Adams (Dallas banker) C. E. Ayres (University of Texas professor) M. G. Bardwell (Smaller War Plants Corporation) (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Interview notes, Robert Briggs (Rancher) (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Interview notes, Tom Connally (U.S. Senator) George Cottingham (Editor, Houston Chronicle) Harry Crozier (Unemployment Compensation Commission) (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Interview notes, J. Frank Dobie (University of Texas professor) Joseph Evans (Houston Cotton Exchange) Fisher E. Heinsohn (Methodist minister) (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - Interview notes, Paul Holcomb (Editor, Austin State Observer) Eugene Howe (Publisher, Amarillo Daily News) Jesse Jones (Houston financier) (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - Interview notes, Ernst Kunz (San Antonio hotelman) R. E. Lucey (Roman Catholic Archbishop) J. S. McNeill (San Antonio Light) (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - Interview notes, Robert Montgomery (University of Texas professor) (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - Interview notes, Frank Overturf (Farmers Union official) Edward Pooley (Editor, El Paso Herald-Post) Sam Rayburn (U.S. Congressman) (Box 40, Folder 20)
    - Interview notes, Frank Rosengren (San Antonio bookdealer) Blake Smith (Baptist minister) J. Lee Smith (Lieutenant-governor) (Box 40, Folder 21)
    - Interview notes, Coke Stevenson (Governor) Don Weaver (Editor, Fort Worth Press) Carter Wesley (Publisher, Houston Informer) Miscellaneous (Box 40, Folder 22)
    - Notes of talk with C.I.O. officials; notes from an "El Paso lunch" (Box 40, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous notes Names, outlines (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - Subseries 55: Research Notes-Utah
    - Interview notes, Joseph Cannon (Commissioner of Publicity) George Corey (Utah Power & Light Co. attorney) James Dillon (Geneva Steel Co. executive) Arthur Gaeth (Radio commentator) (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Interview notes, Grover Giles (Attorney General) R. Grant Ivins (Brigham Young University professor) (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Interview notes, F. H. Knickerbocker (Union Pacific official) Herbert Maw (Governor) Evan Peters (Washington State businessman) (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Interview notes, Mark Peterson (Editor, Deseret News; an Apostle) Jennings Phillips (Braun & Co., Public Relations) (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Interview notes, George Albert Smith (President, Mormon Church) I. A. Smoot (Salt Lake City postmaster) Elbert Thomas (U.S. Senator) William Wallace (Democratic Party official) Miscellaneous (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Notes on Bingham Copper Mines Miscellaneous notes Names, outline (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 56: Research Notes-Vermont
    - Interview notes, Ralph Flanders (U.S. Senator) Mortimer Proctor (Governor-elect) William Wills (governor) Miscellaneous Miscellaneous notes (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 57: Research Notes-Virginia
    - Interview notes, Virginius Dabney (Editor, Richmond Times-Dispatch) (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Interview notes, Josephus Daniels (Editor, Raleigh, N.C., News &Observer) Colgate Darden (governor) H.W. Jackson (Tobacco company official) Douglas Southall Freeman (author) Miscellaneous notes Outline (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 58: Research Notes-Washington
    - Interview notes, Jay Allen (journalist) Roy Atkinson (labor leader) James Beck (labor leader) Claire Cochran (Secretary to Senator Magnuson) (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Interview notes, Howard Costigan (Radio commentator) Nelson Hazeltine (Bonneville Power Administration) Nannie Wood Honeyman (Portland Customs Collector) (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Interview notes, Warren Magnuson (U.S. Senator) Jerry O'Connell (Democratic Party official) Evans Peters (businessman) Miscellaneous (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous notes Names, outline (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 59: Research Notes-West Virginia
    - Interview notes, C. E. Hodges (Charleston Chamber of Commerce) Harley Kilgore (U.S. Senator) (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Interview notes, C. W. Meadows Miscellaneous notes (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 60: Research Notes-Wisconsin
    - Interview notes, Thomas Coleman (Industrialist) William Evjue (Editor, Madison Capital Times) (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - Interview notes, Philip La Follette (governor) Robert La Follette, Jr. (U.S. Senator) (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - Interview notes, Cyrus Philipp (Republican Party official) Morris Rubin (Editor, The Progressive) (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous notes Names (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - Subseries 61: Research Notes-Wyoming
    - Interview notes, William Grove (Radio station manager) Lester Hunt (governor) (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - Interview notes, Mrs. R. F. Love (Wyoming State Tribune & Leader) Tracy McCraken (Democratic National committeeman) Joseph O'Mahoney (U.S. Senator) Miscellaneous Miscellaneous notes Names (Box 41, Folder 21)
  - Subseries 62: Research Notes-New England
    - Interview notes, Robert Blood (Governor, New Hampshire) Sevellon Brown (Publisher, Providence Journal) Erwin Canham (Editor, Christian Science Monitor) Karl Compton (President, Mass. Institute of Technology) Charles Curtis (writer) (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Interview notes, Ralph Flanders (U.S. Senator, Vermont) Carl Friedrich (Harvard University professor) Russell Gerould (Secretary to Gov. of Massachusetts) J. M. Langley (Editor, Concord, N.H., Daily Monitor) (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Interview notes, Kenneth Murdock (Harvard University professor) Summer Sewell (governor, Maine) Harry Sherman (Editor, Hartford, Conn., Courant) Miscellaneous (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous notes Outlines (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 63: Research Notes-Midwest
    - Interview notes, Frank Bane (Council of State Governments) Lucile Bluford (Kansas City (Mo.) Call) David Connery (Michigan labor leader) Morris Ernst (New York lawyer) Thomas Finletter (New York lawyer) (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Interview notes, Richard Finnegan (Editor, Chicago Times) Flynn Robert Hutchins (Chancellor, University of Chicago) J. E. Lawrence (Editor, Lincoln (Nebr.) Star) Lloyd Lewis (journalist) (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Interview notes, Milton Meyer (Chicago writer) Roderick Peattie (Ohio State University Professor) Pierson (Cincinnati banker) Andrew Schoeppel (Kansas governor) (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Interview notes, Miscellaneous (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous notes Outlines (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 64: Research Notes-Northwest
    - Interview notes, Jay Allen (writer) Roy Atkinson (Washington labor leader) Ivan Bloch (Bonneville Power Administration official) Thomas Campbell (Wheat farmer) George Corey (Utah Power & Light Co. attorney) (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Interview notes, Howard Costigan (Washington radio commentator) Dickinson J. B. Ellis (Cincinnati City Solicitor) (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Interview notes, Nelson Hazeltine (Bonneville Power Administration official) (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Interview notes, Nannie Wood Honeyman (Portland Collector of Customs) S. E. Hutton (Bureau of Reclamation, Coulee Dam) John Kuhns (Oregon forester) John McGregor (Wheat farmer) (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - Interview notes, John McKee (President, Portland Utilities Co.) Warren Magnuson (U.S. Senator, Washington) Wayne Morse (U.S. Senator, Oregon) Richard Neuberger (Oregon State Senator) (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - Interview notes, Jerry O'Connell (Washington Democratic Party Official) B. Pearce (Washington Public Utilities District) Evan Peters (Washington businessman) Miscellaneous (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - Notes on fish and fishing; power and public utilities; Boeing Aircraft Co. (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - Notes on farming and wheat (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - Subseries 65: Research Notes-West
    - Interview notes, Ben Cherrington (Acting Chancellor, University of Denver) Howard Costigan (Washington radio commentator) Roscoe Fleming (writer) R. E. Warren (Colorado State Publicity Director) (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - Interview notes, Miscellaneous (Box 42, Folder 19)
    - Miscellaneous notes Outline (Box 42, Folder 20)
  - Subseries 66: Research Notes-South
    - Interview notes, Carl Bailey (former Arkansas governor) W. W. Ball (Editor, Charleston (S.C.) News & Courier) Virginius Dabney (Editor, Richmond Times-Dispatch) Josephus Daniels (Editor, Raleigh (N.C.) News & Observer) Colgate Darden (Virginia governor) (Box 42, Folder 21)
    - Interview notes, Douglas S. Freeman (author) (Box 42, Folder 22)
    - Interview notes, George Mitchell (Labor leader) (Box 42, Folder 23)
    - Interview notes, Howard Odum (University of North Carolina Professor) Claude Pepper (U.S. Senator, Florida) Lillian Smith (author) (Box 42, Folder 24)
    - Interview notes- Miscellaneous (Box 42, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous notes Outlines (Box 42, Folder 26)
  - Subseries 67: Research Notes-Negroes
    - Interview notes, R. E. Clement (President, Atlanta University) Virginius Dabney (Editor, Richmond Times-Dispatch) Margaret Fisher (writer) Douglas S. Freeman (author) (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Interview notes, Frank Graham (President, University of North Carolina) Oliver Harrington (N.A.A.C.P. official) Guy Johnson (Director, Southern Regional Council) Harrison Jones (Chairman of Board, Coca Cola Co.) (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Interview notes, Benjamin Mays (President, Morehouse College) George Mitchell (Labor leader) Howard Odum (University of North Carolina professor) John Paschall (Editor, Atlanta Journal) (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Interview notes, F. B. Patterson (President, Tuskegee Institute) (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Interview notes, Josephine Pinckney (author) Lillian Smith (author) (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Interview notes, Chauncey Sparks (Alabama governor) Jack Tarver (Atlanta Constitution) (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Interview notes, Walter White (N.A.A.C.P. official) (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Interview notes- Miscellaneous (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous notes Outlines (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 68: Research Notes-Missouri Valley Authority
    - Interview notes, J. H. Becker (MVA Regional Director) Benton Stong (Editor, National Union Farmer) G. S. Warden (Publisher, Great Falls (Mont.) Tribune) Miscellaneous (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous notes Outline (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 69: Research Notes-Tennessee Valley Authority
    - Interview notes, S.A. Harvey (Works Manager, Muscle Shoals) David Lilienthal (Chairman) (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Interview notes, W. H. Landess (TVA official) E. J. Meeman (Editor, Memphis Press-Scimitar) Harcourt Morgan (TVA Director) (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Interview notes, James Pope (TVA Director) F. C. Schlemmer (Project Manager, Fontana Dam) Miscellaneous (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Notes on Muscle Shoals Miscellaneous notes Outlines (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 70: Research Notes-Thomas E. Dewey
    - Interview notes, Thomas E. Dewey (New York Governor) Thomas Finletter (attorney) Robert Moses (State and local official) Miscellaneous Miscellaneous notes (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 71: Research Notes-Henry J. Kaiser
    - Interview notes, Clay Bedford (Kaiser Co. official) George Cameron (Publisher, San Francisco Chronicle) Vance Fawcett (Kaiser Co. official) (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - Interview notes, C. J. Haggerty (California labor leader) Henry J. Kaiser (Industrialist) George Roberts (California labor leader) Miscellaneous (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Subseries 72: Research Notes-Harold Stassen
    - Interview notes, Joseph Ball (U.S. Senator, Minnesota) Elmer Benson (former governor, Minnesota) John Jacobsen (Minnesota labor leader) Walter Judd (U.S. Congressman, Minnesota) (Box 43, Folder 19)
    - Interview notes, Mark Nolan (Minnesota judge) William Parker (Minnesota Republican State Chairman) Roger Rutchik (Secretary to Gov. Benson) (Box 43, Folder 20)
    - Interview notes, Gideon Seymour (Editor, Minneapolis Star-Journal) (Box 43, Folder 21)
    - Interview notes, Harold Stassen (former governor, Minnesota) J. R. Wiggins (Editor, St. Paul Pioneer Press) Miscellaneous (Box 43, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous notes Outlines (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - Subseries 73: Research Notes-Arthur Vandenberg
    - Interview notes, Arthur Vandenberg (U.S. Senator, Michigan) (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - Subseries 74: Miscellaneous Materials
    - Miscellaneous interview notes, miscellaneous notes on Introduction and Conclusion (Box 43, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous outlines, schedules, agendas, names (Box 43, Folder 26)
    - Notes on possible libel (Box 43, Folder 27)
- Series VI: Death Be Not Proud
  DEATH BE NOT PROUD is a different type of work than any of Gunther's other books. It is a personal memoir and a memorial to Gunther's son, John, Jr., who died in 1947 of a brain tumor after a long and courageous struggle. The original manuscript of DEATH BE NOT PROUD is not a part of the papers deposited with the University of Chicago. Gunther donated the manuscript to the New York Public Library. However, a carbon copy of the original manuscript is included. The printer's copy and galley or page proofs were not a part of the original deposit.
  The research notes for this work are, of course, very different from those in the rest of the collection. Included in this section are school and camp reports, medical reports, correspondence with doctors, and numerous longhand notes. These longhand notes, which had been cut into small pieces, record Gunther's own memories, the recollections of Frances Gunther, and of others, including Johnny himself, who kept a diary, of the events which transpired during the long illness. These notes have been arranged chronologically, as they were when deposited.
  The correspondence is the most extensive part of the material on this work. There are two folders of personal correspondence, all post-publication, from friends of Gunther commenting on the book. There are also four boxes, containing approximately four thousand letters from the general public. The book obviously evoked strong feelings on the part of the readers. The letters are from people who had suffered similar tragedies, some whose relatives were then suffering from cancer, letters of general sympathy from children and adults from all over the world. The book had been condensed in The Ladies' Home Journal, in the Readers' Digest and its eleven international editions, and later in Coronet, thus having a very wide circulation. The correspondence has been arranged alphabetically within each alphabetical letter. One folder of letters has been segregated. They were used in the introduction to the second edition published in 1953. There is also one folder of letters to Lewis Gannett who wrote a review of the book for the New York Herald-Tribune, and one folder containing letters to Gunther on an article entitled "The Cancer in our Breasts," which was published in McCall's Magazine in 1950.
  The material for the book is contained in five boxes.
  - Subseries 1: Original Manuscript
    - Foreword, Chapter 1 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Chapters 2-3 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Chapters 4-5 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Aftermath, Part Two (Letters), The Diary (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 2: Research Notes
    - School and camp reports on John Jr., 1938-1947 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Medical Reports and Autopsy; 1946-1947; Death Certificate, Funeral (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence to JG from doctors, 1946-1947 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Notes (handwritten) on Part I (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Notes on Part 2-April-May 1946 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Notes on Part 2-June-August 1946 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Notes on Part 2-September 1946-February 1947 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Notes on Part 2-March-May 1947 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Notes on Part 2-June 1947 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Notes on Part 2-Funeral (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - Notes on Part 2-Questions to doctors and JG notes on answers (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - Notes on Part 2-Chronology (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - Notes on Part 2-Notes on the 1st draft (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - Notes on Part 2-Carbon copy (1st draft) Frances Gunther chapter (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - Notes on Part 2-Notes by Frances (Box 44, Folder 19)
    - Notes on Part 2-Material in Johnny's handwriting (Box 44, Folder 20)
    - Clippings-Obituaries (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - Subseries 3: Correspondence
    - Personal Correspondence A-N (Box 44, Folder 22)
    - Personal Correspondence N-Z (Box 44, Folder 23)
  - Subseries 4: Post-publication Correspondence
    - A (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - B (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - B (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - B (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - C (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - C (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - D (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - E (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - F (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - F (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - G (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - G (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - H (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - H (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - H (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - I-J (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - K (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - K (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - L (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - L (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - M (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - M (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - M (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - M (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - N (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - O (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - P (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - P (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - R (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - R (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - S (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - S (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - S (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - T (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - U-V (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - W (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - W (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - W (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Y-Z (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - UNSIGNED (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Letters used in introduction to 2nd Edition 1953 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - Letters to Lewis Gannett on review of Death Be Not Proud (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Letters to JG about his McCall's article on Cancer (1950) (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Copy of script of radio reading, University of North Carolina (Box 48, Folder 14)
- Series VII: Behind the Curtain
  The papers concerning BEHIND THE CURTAIN, published in 1949, are contained in five boxes. Like several other of Gunther's books, BEHIND THE CURTAIN was first conceived as a series of articles for Look magazine and the New York Herald-Tribune. In arranging the manuscripts, the Look and Herald-Tribune articles are included as the original manuscript. Gunther, in most cases, pasted the published versions onto pieces of paper and then heavily revised them. More than half the book, however, is new material. The manuscripts are as follows:
  1. Original manuscript-Look magazine articles-however, only four of the manuscripts of the nine articles are included.
  2. Original manuscript-New York Herald-Tribune articles, published under the general title "Inside Europe Today."
  3. First Revision or Second Draft, which is the original manuscript for the book version, including revisions of above articles and additions.
  4. Printer's copy, with author's corrections.
  The correspondence concerning this book is not extensive, but among the more interesting letters are those from M. W. Fodor, a long-time European journalist connected with the American Military Government for Germany, and a letter from Dr. W. C. Weiskopf, Minister Plenipotentiary of Czechoslovakia to the United States.
  The interview notes are of special interest. Gunther talked with most of the leaders of Europe during his preparation for the book. Among the many statesmen, journalists, businessmen, and others whom Gunther interviewed are Pope Pius XII, Prime Minister Alcide de Gasperi of Italy, Marshal Josip Tito of Yugoslavia, Matyas Rakosi, communist leader of Hungary, American Ambassador to Czechoslovakia Laurence Steinhardt, General Lucius Clay, American Military Governor of Germany, and Jacques Soustelle, Gaullist leader in France.
  - Subseries 1: Original Manuscripts-Look Magazine Articles
    - "War or Peace in Europe?" (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - "USA versus Russia in Berlin" (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - "Behind the Curtain" (2 drafts) (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - "The Man Who Rules Italy." (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous pages from Look dispatches. (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 2: Original Manuscripts-Herald Tribune Series-"Inside Europe Today"
    - Article 1 (1st & 2nd drafts), untitled ("Open War Unlikely") (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Article 2 "Italy-Men and Issues" ("Italy-Issues and Impressions") (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Article 3 "Italy-Communists and Catholics" ("Italy-Communists,Catholics and U.S.") (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Article 4 "Italy-What's Left of Fascism" (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Article 5 Untitled ("Orient Express") (1st and 2nd drafts) (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Article 6 "Tito and Yugoslavia" (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Article 7 "Men Around Tito" (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Article 8 "Man Who Rules Hungary" (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - Article 9 1st and 2nd drafts, Untitled ("Poland") (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - Article 10 1st and 2nd drafts, Untitled ("Czechoslovakia") (Box 49, Folder 15)
    - Article 11 "France" (Box 49, Folder 16)
    - Article 12 "England" (Box 49, Folder 17)
    - Unpublished articles-First and Second articles on Berlin (Box 49, Folder 18)
    - Published Herald Tribune Articles (Box 49, Folder 19)
  - Subseries 3: Original Manuscripts-Behind the Curtain
    - Table of Contents, Acknowledgments (Several versions) (Box 49, Folder 20)
    - Chapter 1 "Introduction-Italy as Breakwater" (Box 49, Folder 21)
    - Chapter 2 "Orient Express" (Box 49, Folder 22)
    - Chapter 3 "Chinks in the Curtain, Plus Certain Observations" (Box 49, Folder 23)
    - Chapter 4 "Yugoslavia, the How and Why" (Box 49, Folder 24)
    - Chapter 5 "Tito" (Box 49, Folder 25)
    - Chapter 6 "The Cominform Rupture" (Box 49, Folder 26)
    - Chapter 7 "Men Around Tito" (Box 49, Folder 27)
    - Chapter 8 "Other Leaders, Other Satellites" (Box 49, Folder 28)
    - Chapter 9 "From Zagreb to Budapest" (Box 49, Folder 29)
  - Subseries 4: First Revision
    - Chapter 10 "The American War in Greece" (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 11 "Talking Turkey" (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 12 "Hungarian New World" (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 13 "The Man Who Rules Hungary" (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 14 "The Czechoslovak Tragedy" (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 15 "Warsaw Redivivus" (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 16 "More About the Poles" (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 17 "Vienna Still Alive" (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 18 "Confusions and Perplexities in Germany" (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 19 "Footnote on Russian Attitudes and Policy" (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 20 "Conclusion-Cut to France and England" (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 5: Printer's Copy
    - Acknowledgements, Table of Contents (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 1 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Chapter 2 (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - Chapter 3 (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - Chapter 4 (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - Chapter 5 (Box 50, Folder 17)
    - Chapter 6 (Box 50, Folder 18)
    - Chapter 7 (Box 50, Folder 19)
    - Chapter 8 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 9 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 10 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 11 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 12 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 13 (2 versions) (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 14 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 15 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 16 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 17 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 18 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Chapter 19 (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 20 (Box 51, Folder 13)
    - Marginal notations on uncorrected carbon of Printer's copy by Jane Gunther or Cass Canfield (Only pages with notations) (Box 51, Folder 14)